<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jahongir Rahmonov</title><link href="http://rahmonov.me/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://rahmonov.me/feeds/non-tech.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://rahmonov.me/</id><updated>2015-06-06T20:36:00+05:00</updated><entry><title>Why I want to work at Google - My validation</title><link href="http://rahmonov.me/posts/why-i-want-to-work-at-google/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-06-06T20:36:00+05:00</published><updated>2015-06-06T20:36:00+05:00</updated><author><name>Jahongir Rahmonov</name></author><id>tag:rahmonov.me,2015-06-05:posts/why-i-want-to-work-at-google/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Those who know me are aware that I would really like to work at Google someday.
Most probably, they think that it is because of the &lt;a href="http://www.glassdoor.com/Salary/Google-Software-Engineer-Salaries-E9079_D_KO7,24.htm"&gt;money&lt;/a&gt;,
all those &lt;a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/google-employees-favorite-perks-2014-7"&gt;perks&lt;/a&gt;,
free food and my resume that will be more or less set for life. All that stuff sounds great and it does influence my desire to some extent.
I won’t deny that. However, none of that matters quite as much to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest reason for me is my validation. I am not one of those people who has been programming since before
high school and I am no genius. In fact, until two years ago I thought I would major in economics and work in
some bank in the future. If we do the math, I have only been programming for a little more than a year now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides, I am not good at anything else either. Communication – not so much. Personal life – in ruins. 
Looks – OK. As you can imagine, I am a very insecure person. I have got to be one of the most insecure people I 
know of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, Google is a top-tier company for top-tier engineers. Being offered a Software Engineer position by 
Google would finally give me something to be really proud of. Something to point to and say to myself 
“Look man, you did that. You are worth something really great!”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t see this happening in the near future and even ever. Because I am not a Google-caliber engineer and not
sure that I will ever be. But, you know what, I will try and keep trying till the day I die. I don’t want to 
be lying at death bed and remember myself as coward because what is at stake is my self-worth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The beginning of the journey&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, here it is. This is what Google means to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I created this blog to write about the things I learn and life experiences that happen to me on this journey 
of validating myself, in hopes that somebody will benefit from these and get there faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s get started!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quote: “A journey of thousand miles begins with a single step.” – Laozi (Chinese philosopher)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fight on!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="google"></category><category term="journey"></category></entry></feed>